priacta.com 2008-01-31

# Priacta Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy for Priacta, Inc.

#### October 30, 2007

At Priacta we recognize that privacy is important. In order to provide our services to you, the user, it is often necessary for us to collect personal information from you. Our goal is to provide you with the services you need while maintaining the highest possible level of integrity and security of user data.

This Privacy Policy applies to all services, websites, and products offered to you through Priacta (collectively referred to as "services").

Should you have any questions regarding this policy, please write to us at :

Data Integrity  
Priacta, Inc.  
2975 Elioch Manor Drive  
Powhatan, VA 23139

or e-mail dataintegrity@priacta.com. You may also contact us via our main website, [www.priacta.com](http://www.priacta.com/).

### Information We Collect

Priacta does not knowingly collect information from or provide services to children under the age of thirteen for any reason. In addition, Priacta is not at this time a member of Safe Harbor and therefore does not at this time knowingly provide services to members of the European Union. By using our services, you assert that you are at least thirteen years of age and are legally able to purchase/use Priacta products and services according to current trade agreements and restrictions.

In order to provide our full range of services, we may collect the following types of information:

#### Information You Provide

When you use a Priacta service that requires registration, we ask you for personal information (such as your name, email address, and account password). For certain services, such as purchasing a product or service, we also request credit card or other payment information which we maintain on secure servers.

#### Log Information

Our servers automatically record information that your Internet browser sends whenever you visit a website. This information, such as web request, Internet Protocol address, browser type, etc., is potentially personally identifying, but we will never use this information to personally identify you.

#### Cookies

When you visit Priacta, we send one or more cookies-a small file containing a string of characters-to your computer to uniquely identify your browser. We use cookies to improve the quality of our service by storing user preferences and tracking user trends. If you choose, you can disable this feature to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some Priacta features and services may not function properly if disabled.

#### Communication

When you communicate with Priacta or other people using Priacta services, we may retain those communications in order to process inquires, respond to requests and improve our services.

Priacta provides an online forum to expedite technical support, provide information that may be useful to you, and allow you to communicate with other visitors. While we monitor forum communications, we are not liable for anything that our guests post or communicate. We do not affirm the correctness or advisability of using any information not provided directly by Priacta. This includes, but is not limited to, advice, technical information, and/or code. If you find something on a Priacta website offensive, obscene, incorrect, or otherwise dissatisfactory, please inform Priacta immediately.

Any information you provide in our public forum is public and will not be protected by Priacta. You have sole responsibility for anything you post and for protecting information that is potentially sensitive.

#### Remote Connect

We sometimes offer the option of connecting to your computer remotely. We will only use this service as specified above, namely to fulfill our obligations to you (e.g., providing technical support) and/or to improve our services.

Priacta requires your explicit, opt-in consent immediately before each remote connection session. We treat all client data, personal and business information on your computer or network as strictly confidential. You are responsible to secure data that you do not want us to access before permitting a Priacta representative to log in to your computer.

If you are a business or corporate user, be aware that insufficient security which allows us access to others' sensitive data may be in violation of privacy or confidentiality agreements to which you have agreed. We are not liable for your breech of contract in the event that we unintentionally access sensitive information. You are welcome and encouraged to supervise our activity, expecially if you have highly sensitive information on your computer.

#### Registration Keys

Priacta issues software Registration Keys, which are associated with customer records and site licenses. We may track product support and update request volume associated with a particular registration key to ensure that the support burden is consistent with the software licensing terms. If we determine that a key may be compromised (hacked or stolen, for example), we may disable support for that key. If so, we will use the identifying information to contact the owner to arrange for a replacement and avoid interruption of service.

#### Links

Priacta may present links in a format that enables us to track whether or not these links have been followed. We use this information to improve our services and transact business with other companies, such as affiliates.

#### Other Sites

This Privacy Policy applies to all websites and services that are owned and operated by Priacta.

### How It Is Used

Priacta processes personal information for the purposes described or implied in the applicable product description, End User License Agreement, Privacy Policy, and/or privacy notice for specific services. In addition to the above, such purposes include:

  * Providing our products and services, including the display of customized content and advertising;
  * Auditing, research and analysis in order to maintain, protect and improve our services;
  * Ensuring the technical functionality and integrity of our network; and
  * Developing new services.

We will never sell, rent, lease, intentionally compromise, or share information with third parties except: 1) when necessary to fulfill our obligations to the user, 2) when necessary to uphold and protect our rights or responsibilities and the rights of our other users, 3) to enforce or comply with law, contract, and/or company standards, or 4) when the user requests that we do so.

### Ensuring Information Protection and Accuracy

Priacta ascribes to the principles of Onward Transfer, Choice, Notice, Access, Data Integrity, Security, and Enforcement as are contained within the US Department of Commerce's Safe Harbor program. However, Priacta is currently NOT currently registered as part of Safe Harbor and, as such, does not at this time knowingly provide services to members of the European Union.

#### Your Information and Third Parties / Onward Transfer

In some cases, we may process personal information to provide services to you in behalf of and according to the instruction of a third party, such as our affiliates. In the event that Priacta is the third party to your information, all the rights, privileges and responsibilities noted in this Privacy policy apply to you.

In some cases, we provide personal information to our affiliated companies and/or other trusted businesses or individuals for the purpose of processing personal information on our behalf.

We assume that these parties will process such information based on our instructions, in the spirit of and compliance with this Policy and any other confidentiality or security measures, including contracts between the third party and Priacta. This is necessary in order to (among other reasons) process financial information in payment of services and to prepare legal forms with the aid of competent personnel.

Of necessity, we reserve the right to disclose personal information if we have reasonable cause to believe that access, use, preservation or disclosure of such information is necessary to comply with law, regulation, legal process or enforceable government request, b) to enforce contract or Terms of Service, c) to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security, or technical issues, or d) to protect against imminent harm to the rights, property, or safety of Priacta, its users or the public as required or permitted by law.

Should Priacta at any time become part of a merger, sale, or acquisition in any form of some of all of its assets, we will provide reasonable notice before personal information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

See section "How It Is Used" above for additional details on our company security standards concerning Third Parties.

#### Choice/Consent

If, at any time, you wish for your information to not be shared with a third party, you may make that request. However, Priacta reserves the right to refuse when doing so would 1) infringe upon the rights of the company or the rights of other users, 2) or violate law. The user accepts that such a request, if granted, may limit or incapacitate the ability of Priacta to provide services to that user.

Use of any of Priacta's services indicates consent of this Privacy Policy and any other applicable notices.

#### Notice/Awareness

We make reasonable attempts to give notice before collecting personal information. You are responsible to read notices and understand their content. Log Information, Cookies, Communication you initiate, and Links, are excluded from this standard because notice is not generally expected, reasonable, and/or convenient for the user.

The reasons for which we collect information about our users are accepted as generally understood or self-evident. Even so, the purposes for our collection of this information are clearly outlined within this policy. Should the user have additional questions or complaints about their personal information and how it is used, you may contact us as noted at the beginning of this policy.

#### Access

Naturally, we wish to collect, use, and maintain only accurate information about our consumers and guests. If you believe that information we have collected is incomplete, inaccurate, or out-of-date, feel free to contact Data Integrity (at contact information above).

Our users may have access to personal information they have voluntarily submitted to Priacta. Priacta reserves the right to refuse user access to personal information 1) when the burden or expense of providing that access is disproportionate to the risks to the individual user's privacy, 2) where the rights of the company or other users would be violated, 3) or when providing such access would violate law.

To help ensure confidentiality and user privacy, Priacta reserves the right to require reasonable verification of user identity when requests for access to personal information are made to verify that only authorized personnel have access to your user data. When verifying your identity, we will never ask for information that we do not already have on file.

Priacta reserves the right to refuse to give reason for denial of access to personal records. In such a case, users may challenge such a refusal through appropriate channels, federally, locally, or through a recognized arbitration service.

If you have concerns about the validating information we request, suspect that someone is trying to collect information that they are not entitled to access, or that your data has been compromised please immediately contact us at dataintegrity@priacta.com.

#### Data Integrity

Any information which Priacta collects is relevant for the purposes stated for its use. Priacta makes a reasonable effort to ensure that user data is accurate and complete at the time of submission. It is also the responsibility of the user to help ensure the accuracy and completeness of information at the time of submission as well as to ensure that such information remains up-to-date.

#### Security

Priacta takes appropriate precautions to protect user data and personal information from loss and misuse as well as unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction.

This includes restricting access of such information to Priacta employees, contractors, agents, and third parties who need to know that information in order to provide or develop services and to maintain user and company rights and obligations. All individuals who have access to this information are bound by confidentiality agreements and are subject to discipline, including termination of applicable contract with Priacta and criminal prosecution, should they fail to keep these agreements.

Other measures which are taken to ensure the security of user data include secure data storage, collection, and processing practices as well as physical security measures to prevent unauthorized access both on-site and via the Web. Priacta agrees to voluntarily review company security practices as needed to ensure reasonable security.

### Complaint Resolution and Policy Enforcement

Should a user at any time have a complaint regarding Priacta services, the user agrees to make a reasonable attempt to contact Priacta first, as stated at the start of this policy, to attempt reasonable resolution of the issue.

If, after reasonable attempts have been made, no successful resolution of the issue can be made, we invite the user to contact the American Arbitration Association at http://www.adr.org/. American Arbitration Association is an independent dispute resolution service. The user also has the alternative of seeking assistance from appropriate local and federal regulatory authorities. Priacta agrees to cooperate with appropriate complaint resolution channels regarding any complaints which could not be worked out between the Priacta and the user. The user agrees to be liable for the cost of arbitration and the user's legal fees, if any.

Any provision of this policy found by a tribunal of competent jurisdiction to be illegal or unenforceable shall be automatically conformed to the minimum requirements of law and all other provisions shall remain in full force and effect.

### Changes to This Policy

This policy may change from time to time. We anticipate that most changes will be minor and will be in the best interest of the user. The most current Policy will remain posted on our website. Users are invited to check for updates regularly. Each policy will be identified at the top of the page by its effective date and all prior versions of our policies will be kept on file, available for view by the user upon request.

If changes are made to this Policy, we will rely on user-provided information to inform you of Policy changes. You are responsible to maintain your contact information. Whether or not we can reach you at the information you have provided, continued use of our services constitutes acceptance of the current policy.

### Miscellaneous

#### Links

We may provide links to third parties. While we try to only affiliate with beneficial and reputable companies, individuals, and websites, we are not responsible for the services, content, security, reliability or advisability of these websites and recommend that you use caution when following links or browsing outside our control.
